<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-10-06T20:41:19+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">Kasimir Suter Winter</title><subtitle>My personal piece of the web. Come join my explorations into design, architecture, coding and life.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">What are problems and what can we do about them?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/design%20thinking/2018/10/28/What-are-Problems-and-What-Should-we-do-About-Them.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What are problems and what can we do about them?" /><published>2018-10-28T11:06:38+00:00</published><updated>2018-10-28T11:06:38+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/design%20thinking/2018/10/28/What-are-Problems-and-What-Should-we-do-About-Them</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/design%20thinking/2018/10/28/What-are-Problems-and-What-Should-we-do-About-Them.html">&lt;p&gt;When we think about problems in the world. We often want to remedy them. To do something which will make them no longer exist. So we commonly use the term “solve” as the action we will take to treat the problem. This sounds very good, “we will solve problems” and it is largely the motto of our scientific technological endeavors. But we must understand the nature of “problems” and the meaning of “solving” a little better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For instance what we call problems are often symptoms, and the true nature of the problem is a cause which we cannot see as easily. If you are to receive a tooth filling, you may think you have solved the problem, however you are only treating the symptom. To truly do away with the problem of cavities, we must redesign the behavior which is the cause of cavities. Namely, brushing your teach regularly and eating less candy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This brings me to four different ways problems can be treated:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Absolution.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Resolution.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Solution.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dissolution.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Absolution&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Absolution means to ignore a problem and hope it will solve itself or go away of its own accord.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Resolution&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Resolution, your 2nd problem solving option, means to  employ behavior previously used in similar situations, adapted if  necessary, so as to obtain an outcome that is good enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This approach to problems relies heavily on experience, trial and  error, qualitative judgment, and so-called common sense. It is the  approach to problems most commonly used by those who govern and those  who manage public processes. Moreover, this approach has little lasting  power because it deals with symptoms and short-term effects, but does  not eliminate the cause of a problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Solution&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Solution means to  discover or create behavior that yields the best, or approximately the  best, possible outcome, one that “optimizes” the situation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Problem solving usually involves research, often using experimentation, quantitative analysis, and uncommon sense.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, few problems, once solved, stay that way. Solutions deteriorate by causes like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Changes in the environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Changing societal goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moreover, solutions generally do not exist in isolation from  other problems. Solutions obtained to problems isolated from the other  problems with which they interact generally produce one or more new  problems. These are often more serious and difficult to solve than the  original problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Dissolution&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dissolution, means to  redesign either the society that has the problem or its environment in  such a way as to eliminate the problem or the conditions that caused it,  thus enabling the society involved to do better in the future than the  best it can do today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The methodologies used to do this are called &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Design_thinking&quot; title=&quot;Design Thinking on Wikipedia&quot;&gt;Design Thinking&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Systems_theory&quot; title=&quot;Systems Theory on Wikipedia&quot;&gt;System Thinking&lt;/a&gt;. They are not always easy ways of thinking, but the rewards are well worth your trouble!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This article comes streight out of the thinking of Russell L. Ackoff. Originally trained as an architect, and a pioneer in the field of &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Operations_research&quot; title=&quot;Operations research&quot;&gt;operations research&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Systems_thinking&quot; title=&quot;Systems thinking&quot;&gt;systems thinking&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Management_science&quot; title=&quot;Management science&quot;&gt;management science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can find a really &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=EbLh7rZ3rhU&quot; title=&quot;Russel Ackoff on Youtube&quot;&gt;powerful presentation by him&lt;/a&gt; on YouTube. It is a bit long, but if you found the ideas in this article interesting, I highly recommend the video. He covers these topics and more in very eloquent understandable ways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">When we think about problems in the world. We often want to remedy them. To do something which will make them no longer exist. So we commonly use the term “solve” as the action we will take to treat the problem. This sounds very good, “we will solve problems” and it is largely the motto of our scientific technological endeavors. But we must understand the nature of “problems” and the meaning of “solving” a little better.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/problems-vs-symptoms-featured-image.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Co-creating the Living Social Organism Design Disco</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/design%20disco/2018/07/31/Design-Disco-Co-creating-a-Living-Social-Organism.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Co-creating the Living Social Organism Design Disco" /><published>2018-07-31T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-07-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/design%20disco/2018/07/31/Design-Disco-Co-creating-a-Living-Social-Organism</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/design%20disco/2018/07/31/Design-Disco-Co-creating-a-Living-Social-Organism.html">&lt;p&gt;Over the past three years I have been involved in the co-creation of &lt;a href=&quot;https://designdisco.org&quot; title=&quot;Design Disco&quot;&gt;Design Disco&lt;/a&gt;. No, it is not a disco club. The “Disco” stands for Discovery, although we also like to have a good time. In this post I want to try and outline  some of the lessons I have learned while being part of this experiment, and  my vision for the future of what could come.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First off I should share a bit of what this whole disco things is about. We are a non profit organization with the mission to show people the world through the window of design. Meaning, we essentially want everyone to discover design, and how they can use design thinking in their everyday lives to “dissolve” problems they face.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Schools teach science, humanities, sports, arts, and many other disciplines of thought and activity, however design is largely left out of the curriculum. We believe this needs to change, and so we just started doing it ourselves. It all began as a group of friends in college, visiting high schools and sharing about design through a presentation and an exercise. It was really small, just a fragile idea that was planted like a seed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fast forward to the present moment and we have come a really long way. We have taught over 1,000 students with over 600 volunteer hours by our incredible instructors. We have spread to Norway and Turkey, with around 60 volunteers in total.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is exciting and all, however what have I learned along the way?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;1-start-small&quot;&gt;1 Start small&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This has been a big personal lesson. Often it is very fun to start new projects, and have new ideas. However, if you get hung up on large fantastical ideas, it becomes really overwhelming to bring it back down to earth and take real actions towards achieving all those ideas. So start small, don’t overwhelm yourself. If its meant to happen, it will take off in time. The worst thing to do is squish a good idea because of inpatients, or give up right before things were about to take off. Its a bit like gardening. If you plant a seed, you won’t see any activity for a few days and you might think it is dead. Then all of a sudden, it will sprout and then the growth will continue exponentially until you can hardly believe you thought it was dead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;2-dream-big&quot;&gt;2 Dream big&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This may sound contrary to the previous lesson, however it can be in fact be symbiotic. When starting new projects, the greater part of motivation to bring the idea to life, comes from the big dream of it. The potential you see in that idea. This is really important to catalyze engagement and bring people together around the same vision. It is also important to have a north star, a guiding vision or goal which you can check your progress against. Just remember, the big dream is not a fixed mandate. It can evolve, and most likely will evolve naturally. This is a good thing, its how the team or “social living organism” will grow and evolve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;3-organizationsteams-are-alive&quot;&gt;3 Organizations/teams are alive&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I mentioned the term social living organism. I have learned to see teams and our whole organization as a kind of living organism. Seeing through this lens is crucial to cultivating an adaptive innovative social organism. How we name the world, influences our perception of the world. As Goethe put it, “How we see people is how we treat them, and how we treat them is who they become.” I find this idea can be applied to communities of people. As soon as we see them as alive, we begin to treat them with life, and thus they become more alive. And what is the key characteristic of life? Well that is a much larger question, but in this situation I was thinking it is the capacity to evolve, adapt and collaborate. These are some of the key principles of a living system:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Divergent parts&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Convergent whole&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dynamic relationships&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ongoing self organizing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Put succinctly: A living system integrates divergent parts, into a convergent whole, in dynamic relationship internally and externally, in an ongoing moment-by-moment process of self organizing and self creation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;4-the-greatest-human-motivations-are-intrinsic-not-extrinsic&quot;&gt;4 The greatest human motivations are intrinsic not extrinsic&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being part of an all volunteer organization. I have come to realize that the greatest motivations for people are not extrinsic. Extrinsic motivations will certainly get people moving, but we don’t want to just move. If we are a social living organism, we want to feel, empathize and steer our movement collectively. In order to unlock passion and innovation, we need to help one another find our intrinsic motivations. That which we desire to fulfill in our lives, that which gives us energy and life when we partake in it. Namely, we want to find meaningful, purposeful activities which we can collectively and individually find intrinsic motivations in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;5-for-all-the-intrinsic-motivation-and-nice-ideas-about-living-social-organisms-we-are-all-human&quot;&gt;5 For all the intrinsic motivation and nice ideas about living social organisms. We are all human.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have found it is important to always remember we are all human beings. This translates to many insights.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We all see the world from our own point of view.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We are all free to act from our values.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We all need to have shelter, food and community.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We all make mistakes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We can all learn and change.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We miss understand one another sometimes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We are not as perfect as our dreams.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;But we are all alive (similar to lesson 3).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am sure there are many more lessons and I may come to update this post in the future as they become apparent to me. However for now that feels complete.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have also learned a lot as a living social organism (organization). Although this is a part time activity for all of us, it has begun to grow into more than that. So how do I see the future for this experiment?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The longer I spend thinking and experiencing. The more I can observe and deduce. However, until I step into action, I will never learn. If we are really going to explore and discover design and its meaningful potential in each persons life, I believe we need to understand the underlying architecture of impactful work. From my observations, this architecture is distributed, close to the edges, and on the ground. Making in person contact, learning through doing, sharing experience with many others and playing a dance of personal exploration and collective learning. Collective action, and personal fulfillment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am absolutely sure that design discovery will continue to grow in the world, and I believe that as a movement and as a catalyst,  Design Disco will continue to be apart of that growth. We have a wide field of potential, we are in a space wholly outdated in its methods and practice: education. Our generation is an internet generation, we value experience over possession, networks over hierarchies, and intrinsic over extrinsic motivation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When thinking of the design of this social organism, Design Disco. I envision a  scaled ecosystem of many Design Discovery ventures across the world.  Ranging from supplementary university courses, to high school workshops,  summer programs, team design thinking workshops, conferences on design  and design thinking and much more. I can see an ecosystem, of networks, of collective teams, sharing knowledge internally and externally to  catalyze an exponential growth of access to and understanding of design  thinking. Some very interesting new types of organizing patterns for  distributed self organizing teams are being developed and shared openly  by organizations such as, &lt;a href=&quot;http://opensource.ouishare.net/&quot; title=&quot;Ouishare Open Source&quot;&gt;Ouishare&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://handbook.enspiral.com/&quot; title=&quot;Enspiral Network Handbook&quot;&gt;Enspiral&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://drive.google.com/file/d/0B44XthBdMmN6bGlfdk8zejdSZUU/view&quot; title=&quot;Gini Company Handbook&quot;&gt;Gini&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://drive.google.com/file/d/0B44XthBdMmN6bGlfdk8zejdSZUU/view&quot; title=&quot;Crisp DNA&quot;&gt;Crisp&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://steamcdn-a.akamaihd.net/apps/valve/Valve_NewEmployeeHandbook.pdf&quot; title=&quot;Valve Company Handbook&quot;&gt;Valve&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a plethora of wonderful ideas that come to my mind which I believe will play into the future of Design Disco. Such as: creating new distributed crediting systems for courses so that the majority of learning which takes place outside of universities can be better valued and made visible. Being part of the maker and Fablab movements, bringing design thinking into this space of tinkering and making. Experimenting with new forms of social organizing using new forms of current-sees (symbol systems which make value visible) in order to empower our social living organism to steer itself collectively and in a highly agile fashion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I could go on and on, but I should probably get to working on it already instead of just dreaming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are curious about Design Disco and how you could get involved, please don’t hesitate to get in touch with me via email or on social media. We are always looking for new passionate members, including those who have a background in something other than design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to stay up to date on our development follow us on &lt;a href=&quot;https://facebook.com/designdisco&quot; title=&quot;Design Disco Facebook&quot;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://instagram.com/designdisco_&quot; title=&quot;Design Disco Instagram&quot;&gt;Instagram&lt;/a&gt;. Also check out &lt;a href=&quot;http://designdisco.org/blog&quot; title=&quot;Design Disco Blog&quot;&gt;our blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you very much for reading! I hope that some of what I discussed may have sparked your interest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;inspirations-for-this-article&quot;&gt;Inspirations for this article:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Very geeky talk on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wBlwQpcV95M&quot;&gt;new internet architectures&lt;/a&gt; by Arthur Brock.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Meta Currency &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;talk on the future digital currencies&lt;/a&gt; and how they will allow us to form new social living organisms.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Great video from an Enspiral member about &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=b9ar0HVzNeE&amp;amp;t=981s&quot;&gt;circles of harmless organizing&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fablabs are something I am really excited about always so I’ll just &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fablabs.io/&quot;&gt;through this in here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Over the past three years I have been involved in the co-creation of Design Disco. No, it is not a disco club. The “Disco” stands for Discovery, although we also like to have a good time. In this post I want to try and outline some of the lessons I have learned while being part of this experiment, and my vision for the future of what could come.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/design-disco-featured-image.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Rebuilding my Website with Jekyll and CSS Grid</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2018/03/01/Rebuilding-my-Website-with-Jekyll.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Rebuilding my Website with Jekyll and CSS Grid" /><published>2018-03-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-03-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2018/03/01/Rebuilding-my-Website-with-Jekyll</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018/03/01/Rebuilding-my-Website-with-Jekyll.html">&lt;p&gt;For years I have been struggling with Wordpress and it’s many plugins and themes. This lead me to slowly learn more and more HTML and CSS. I never liked the idea of coding a website from scratch, I felt it was not very efficient. When I learned about &lt;a href=&quot;git-scm.com&quot;&gt;git&lt;/a&gt; I had this idea about how website templates could be built in &lt;a href=&quot;github.com&quot;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt; and then hosted directly from a repository. Using the git workflow, everyone would be able to fork and submit pull requests for any website on the internet. Well, low and behold that literally exists! It is called &lt;a href=&quot;pages.github.com&quot;&gt;Github Pages&lt;/a&gt; and its super cool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/github-pages.png?raw=true&quot; alt=&quot;Github Pages&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The one piece which I had not anticipated, and which made all the difference was &lt;a href=&quot;jekyllrb.com&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;. It is a static site generator which uses &lt;a href=&quot;shopify.github.io/liquid&quot;&gt;Liquid&lt;/a&gt; as a template engine. It is also the static site generator used by &lt;a href=&quot;pages.github.com&quot;&gt;Github Pages&lt;/a&gt;. Jekyll is highly versatile, being able to compile almost any code. This means that it is useful in many different situations, and thus it has been adopted widely. &lt;!-- excerpt --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/jekyll.png?raw=true&quot; alt=&quot;Jekyll&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fast forward four years and its 2018. I finally decided to rebuild my personal website to learn how to use Jekyll and Liquid templating. I was simultaneously inspired by Jen Simmons and her talks about the revolution of CSS Grid. I had always been overwhelmed by the complicated CSS hacks for creating interesting designs. But finally there was a way to do it completely intuitively. This gave me the final motivation to build a Jekyll site, host it on gh pages and build it with CSS Grid. For me this is the ultimate web design combination as it allows for easy remixing of designs since the CSS does not rely on HTML elements for design, and easy access to code, since everything is hosted in a Github repository.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/jen-simmons-layout-lab.png&quot; alt=&quot;Layout Lab&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you for reading, and I hope you get a chance to try out Jekyll. I also  want to through a link in &lt;a href=&quot;www.youtube.com/watch?v=Qof0XB0yaDs&amp;amp;t=825s&quot;&gt;here for a great talk&lt;/a&gt; by Jen Simmons about the future of design on the web.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">For years I have been struggling with Wordpress and it’s many plugins and themes. This lead me to slowly learn more and more HTML and CSS. I never liked the idea of coding a website from scratch, I felt it was not very efficient. When I learned about git I had this idea about how website templates could be built in Github and then hosted directly from a repository. Using the git workflow, everyone would be able to fork and submit pull requests for any website on the internet. Well, low and behold that literally exists! It is called Github Pages and its super cool.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/jekyll-featured-image.png" /></entry></feed>